SULEYMAN ZEYNUL

<u>zeynulsuleyman@gmail.com</u> | +48 666206558 | <u>LinkedIn Profile</u> | <u>GitHub Kaggle</u>

SUMMARY

An enthusiastic, highly motivated Master's graduate in **Finance and Accounting** with proven leadership capabilities, who likes to take initiative, seek out new challenges. Data Analyst and Data Scientist with 1+ years of experience in IT and on **Data Analysis**, **Data Manipulation**, **Data Visualization**, and **Machine Learning**. Expertized in **Python data manipulation** and **machine learning models**, and widely used Python libraries like **NumPy**, **Pandas**, **Matplotlib**, **Plotly**, **Scipy**, and **Seaborn** for data analysis, visualization, and **Sklearn** for ML modelling. Also, have experience with **SQL**, **GSS** and **Tableau** for data analysis and visualization. Offering a good combination of problem-solving, creative thinking, and coding skills.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Clarusway - Virginia, USA (Remote)

May 2021 - Present

Data Analyst Mentor

- Provided technical guidance and mentoring to students to review and assist with projects and exercises.
- Participated in weekly live group mentoring sessions with data analyst candidates and completed indepth capstone projects.
- Extracted, processed and analyzed complex datasets using advanced querying, visualization and analytics tools.
- Traced the progress of each trainee with weekly-based One-on-one sessions.

State Street Bank International GMBH – *Cracow* – *Poland*July 2020 - Present Investment Fund Accountant

- Engaging in daily Net Asset Value Calculation
- Carrying out task within NAV cycle

Hosseven Heating & Insulation Inc. – Bursa - Turkey Import & Export Agent

April 2018 – January 2019

• Handling exporting and importing transactions and daily contacting with customers

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Data Analysis, Business Intelligence, Statistics
- Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Scipy, Plotly, Sklearn
- Python, HTML & CSS, MS SQL Server, SQLite, MySQL
- Tableau, Advance Excel, VBA, Google Sheets, Linux, Git, GitHub
- Jira, Agile Methodology, Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), Scrum, Kanban

SOFT & TRANSFERRABLE SKILLS

 Critical Thinking, Adaptability & Flexibility, Leadership & Team Player, Time Management, Proactive Problem-Solving, Multitasking Skills, Lifelong Learner, Problem Solver

PROJECTS – Data Science

AutoScout Car Price Prediction Model

I reduced the number of features entered by users of a car dealer web page called AutoScout24 while
not compromising the prediction power of my model. I used an original dataset that was scrapped
directly from the given web page.

• After cleaning, data preprocessing, and scaling, I built a Linear, XGBoost, and Random Forest models in Sklearn that could predict a given car's price with 89 percent of accuracy.

Gender Classification Model

- I answered the question of whether a decent gender classifier can be built given a dataset with people's personal preferences.
- After exploratory data analysis of the data, I applied 16 different ML models such as KNeighbors, Logistic, CatBoost, and based on their performances chose ExtraTree model as the core model.

Stroke Prediction Model

 With LogisticRegression, I created a model that can predict whether a patient is likely to get stroke based on features like gender, age, various diseases, and smoking status with a Recall score of 89 percent.

Customer Segmentation Model

- With KMeans and Hierarchical Clustering models, I created a model that segments customers according to the purchasing history obtained from the membership cards of a big mall.
- Based on clustering results, I added my insights to retain existing-high-spending customers and increase the number of such customers with some promotions.

PROJECTS – Data Analysis

- Analyzing Police Activity (Rhode Island): The analysis of the traffic stops in Rhode Island that was collected by the Stanford Open Police Project (*Skills*: Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, and Statistics).
- **Police Fatal Shooting Analysis**: USA fatal police shoot analysis using visualization tools (*Skills*: Pandas, Matplotlib, and Seaborn).
- Analyzing Fandango Movie Ratings: Fandango Movie Rating analysis using visualization tools (*Skills*: Pandas, Matplotlib, and Seaborn).

EDUCATION

Data Science Trainee – Clarusway IT Bootcamp

March 2021 – Present

MA, Finance and Accounting – Akademia Ekomomiczna – Humanistyczna Warsaw, Poland - 2019-2021

BA, Political Science and International Relations – *Yildiz Technical University Istanbul*, *Turkey*, 2013-2017

NOTABLE AWARDS

2017, Graduation as a High Honor Student, Yıldız Technical University 2019, Semifinalist at Ernst & Young's Financial Challenge

LANGUAGE SKILLS

- Turkish *Native*
- English Advance

Spanish - Intermediate